日常工作
翻译：@Phuckq  压制：感康小快客
校对 & 后期：@Phuckq
好啊 好啊
【三次元成瘾者康复中心】倾情奉献
更多动画 新浪@Kresent
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
老兄 我拿到了
Dude, I got them.
"爱之机器人2" 的免费观影券噢
Tickets to a free screening of "Love Bot 2".
哇 赞
Aw, sweet!
第一部弱爆了
The first one was so lame.
窝 湿 机 七 人  窝 不 东 爱
I AM A ROBOT, I CAN NOT LOVE.
快 叫上玛格丽特和艾琳 我们可以一起去找点乐子
Come on, call Margaret and Eileen, we can all go make fun of it.
事实上 我只有两张票 所以我要请玛格丽特跟我去
Actually, I only got two tickets. I'm gonna ask Margaret to go.
搞毛啊你
Aw, what?
我们不是形影不离的好基友吗
But we do everything together.
正是因为你们这群电灯泡 我和玛格丽特才永远不能擦出爱火
Exactly, Margaret and I will never be more than just friends with you guys tagging along.
是时候升华我们的友谊了
It's time to take this to the next level.
好吧 老兄 你爱咋咋地
Alright, man. Do your thing.
好吧 你必须这么做
Okay, you gotta do it.
这么做就对了
You just gotta do it.
妥妥的
You got this.
好啊 老兄 好啊
Yes, dude, yes!
哥们
Dude?
摩迪凯
Mordecai?
老兄 我知道这一定很难受
I know it must hurt, man,
可是你已经把那首歌单曲循环了差不多五天了
but you've been listening to that song on repeat for, like, five days now.
你在吗
Hello?
嗨 伙计
Hey, buddy.
我想说...
So I was thinking...
别这样啊 老兄
Come on, man.
老兄 别这样
Dude, come on.
怎样
What?
我讨厌你变成这副模样 老兄
I'm sick of seeing you like this, man.
愁容满面 自暴自弃 闻起来死气沉沉的
All sad and junk. You smell like something died.
确实死了
Something did die.
我的心 死了
Inside of me. My heart.
别想了啊 你压根不需要心啊
Forget that, you don't need a heart.
你不懂啦 老兄
You don't get it, man.
我此生所爱要结婚了 新郎却不是我
The love of my life is getting married to some other dude.
你能体会这是什么感觉吗
Do you know how that feels?
她是订婚了 那又怎样
She's engaged. So what?
好像你们俩真交往过似的
It's not like you guys are even dating.
好啦好啦 我的错
I'm sorry, okay?
但是 听着 我有个绝妙的解决办法
But listen, I have the perfect solution to your problem.
什么
What?
爱的圈养
"Couple Corral?
找伴儿 就是这么简单
"Where findin' pardners is a fine howdy-do?"
老兄 我可不想网上征友啊
Dude, I'm not gonna start internet dating.
我现在就想一个人待着
I just wanna be alone right now.
再说了 这个网站是为了 牛仔之类的人准备的
Besides, that site is for, like, cowboys or something.
那你就是个牛仔啦 因为我给你注册喽
Well, I guess you're a cowboy, then, 'cause I signed you up!
- 啥   - 没事 老兄 这是合法的网站
- What? - Nah, it's cool, man, it's legit.
快 来看看你的资料
Look, check out your profile.
摩迪酷
"Mordecool?
爱好: 电子游戏 滑板 和烤奶酪
Likes video games, goofin' off and grilled cheese?"
老兄 你让我看上去像个白痴
Dude, you make me sound like a dork!
嘿 我这是实事求是 老兄 这可不能怪我
Hey, all that stuff's true, man. Don't put that on me.
随你吧 老兄
Whatever, man.
这个跟我半毛钱关系都没有
I'm not having anything to do with this.
拜托 快看 已经有10个妹子勾搭你了
Come on! Look, ten girls already responded.
11个了
Eleven!
少来了 我会走出房门冲个澡的
Nah, I'll get out of my room and take a shower,
但是别想我跟陌生人约会
but dates with random strangers?
来嘛兄弟 这说不定会让你好受点
Come on, man, it might make you feel better.
你看 就算不为了自己 也为了我嘛
Look, if you can't do it for yourself, then do for me, man.
别扫我兴啊
You're bummin' me out.
12个喽
Twelve.
餐馆
好吧 我必须得说
Okay, so I just have to say,
过去我都不做这档子事儿的
I usually don't do this sort of thing.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
是呀 我也从来不在外面吃
Yeah. I never eat out like this.
你知道他们都是怎么吐槽高级餐厅的吗
You know what they say about fancy restaurants.
呃 是啊
Ummm...yeah.
噢 所以你赞同女性被大众媒体扭曲报道了
Oh? So you agree that women are misrepresentative forms of popular media?
不知道 也许吧
I don't know. I guess.
那么 到底是怎样
Well, which is it?
你觉得一切进展顺利 还是你根本就讨厌我
You think this is going well or do you hate me?
都有
Both?
好 咱们各付各帐吧
Yeah, we both split it.
我点了沙拉 吃了点你的薯条
I got the salad...Ate some of your fries...
你是...摩迪凯
Are you...Mordecai?
对...你是乌云小洁
Yeah...Cloudy Jay?
那只是我的网名
That's just my screen name.
叫我CJ就好
You can just call me CJ.
抱歉我迟到了 工作忙走不开
Sorry I'm late. I got caught up at work.
噢 是吗
Oh, yeah?
我真希望把工作辞了 每天就看看电视什么的
I wish I could just quit and watch TV all day or something, you know?
哦
Uh-huh.
那么 在公园工作感觉如何呢
So what's it like working at the park?
还成
It's fine.
好吧 这是闹哪样 我看得出来你一点都不感兴趣
Alright, what's the deal? I can tell you're not into this.
啥 不啊
What? No!
老兄 你就对我说实话吧
Dude, just be real with me.
你说得没错 是我朋友劝我来这儿的
You're right. My friend talked me into coming here.
我抑郁了一阵子 需要出门活动活动
I've been depressed and just needed to get out of the house.
抱歉 我确信你是个好姑娘
Sorry, I'm sure you're a cool girl and all,
只是我现在不想和任何人交往
but I'm not interested in dating anyone right now.
没关系的
It's cool.
真的
Really?
是啊 我们可以试着做朋友
Yeah. We can just try being friends.
也许我能帮你扫除阴霾
Maybe I can cheer you up.
走吧 咱们去别的地方
Come on, let's get out of here.
要成功了
You're doing it!
你要打破最高分了
You're gonna beat the high score!
哇 我从没看过别人破这游戏的记录
Wow. I've never seen anybody beat this game before.
是呀 这个我可是行家里手
Yeah...I'm kinda an old pro at this.
平局了 平局了
Tied game, tied game!
你偷袭 你偷袭
Cheap shot, cheap shot!
不 不 我才不管你怎么说
No, no, I don't care what you say.
原版的"僵尸宿命"比翻拍版好太多了
The original "Zombie Destiny" movie is way better than the remake.
嘴里塞着东西的时候别讲话 摩迪酷
Quit talking with your mouth full! Mordecool.
等等 你说什么 我嘴巴张着吗
Wait, what do you mean? My mouth's open?
我不清楚诶 现在还张着吗
I have no idea, is it still open?
噢 恶心 你都多大了啊
Aw, gross. How old are you?
然后他的头就爆炸了 就这么"砰"的一声
Yeah, so his head just exploded...just...blam!
天 你们真是有够倒霉啊
Man! You guys have like the worst luck or something.
对啊 噢 差点忘了
I know. Oh, I almost forgot.
- 我有两张明天去看"爱之机器人2"的票... - 我愿意
- I have these tickets to see "Love Bot 2" tomorrow... - Yes.
啥?
What?
我愿意 我愿意和你一起去看电影
Yes, I'd love to go to the movies with you.
嗯 太好了
Yeah, great.
我不想就这样浪费了
I didn't want them to go to waste,
虽然我不知道这片子怎么样 但是...
so I don't know how good it'll be, but---
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
抱 紧 窝 让 窝 东 得 爱   抱 紧 窝
Hold me so I can learn to love. Hold me.
太经典了 我等不及了
Classic! I can't wait.
好吧 那就定好明晚了
Alright, so tomorrow night?
-没问题 到时候见了   -再见 CJ
- Cool. See you then. - Later, CJ.
摩迪凯 喂
Mordecai! Hey!
嗨 玛格丽特
Hey, Margaret.
你最近跑哪去了 我好像有八百年没看见你了
Where have you been? It feels like I haven't seen you in forever.
就 到处转转呗
Oh, I know, around.
噢 那么 你最好别给我跑到别的地方去喝咖啡
Oh. Well, you better not be getting your coffee from someplace else.
不可能啦
No way.
没了我你们店要怎么活啊
You guys would go out of business without me.
- 噢 我该让你认识认识我的... - 不用了
- Oh. I should introduce you to my... - No!
抱歉 我只是...
Sorry, I just...
有点急事
I'm kinda in a hurry.
- 噢 那么 好吧    - 再见
- Oh. Well, okay. - Catch you later.
再见
Later.
老兄 拜托
Dude, come on!
你做得很好啊
You were doing so well!
摩迪凯
Mordecai!
他还在为了那个卖咖啡的伤心吗
Is he still crying about the coffee girl?
如果我还得再听一遍这首歌的话
If I have to listen to this song one more time...
摩迪凯 开门 你老板来了
Mordecai! This is your boss! Open up!
我请了心理健康假
I'm talking a mental health day.
你压根没资格难过
You don't have the right to be sad.
你从来就没胆子告诉玛格丽特你的感受
You never even had the guts to tell Margaret how you feel.
听着 如果你就这么不管不顾的话
Listen. If you leave things the way they are now,
你的后半生都会在悔恨中度过
you'll regret it for the rest of your life.
告诉她也许并不会改变什么
Telling her might not change anything,
但至少你可以做个了断
but at least you'll have closure.
你该告诉玛格丽特你的感受
You should just tell Margaret how you feel.
你说得对 谢了 跳跳
You're right. Thanks, Skips.
啥
What?
随便你吧 给我把音乐关了
Whatever! Just turn off that music.
好吧 所以 你准备好了吗
Alright, so, you ready?
也许吧
I guess.
别担心 老兄
Don't worry, man.
我随时准备好打120 以防你晕过去或者
I'll be there ready to call an ambulance if you pass out or...
开始发狂之类的
start freaking out or somethin'.
谢了 老兄
Thanks, man.
是啊 然后他就邀请我去看电影
Yeah, and then he asked me to the movies.
这有点怪 不过 也挺好的 你懂的
It was kind of awkward, but cute. You know.
我的天 他在那儿
Oh, my gosh! There he is!
那个就是他
That's him!
我要过去跟他打个招呼
I'm gonna go say hi real quick.
玛格丽特
Margaret!
嗨 来得正好
Hey, guys, good timing.
玛格丽特 听着
Margaret, listen,
有件事我一直都想告诉你
there's something I've been meaning to tell you for a long time.
好啊 不过能不能先等下
Sure, but can it wait a sec?
我想给你们介绍个人
There's someone I want you guys to meet.
这个是我弟弟 约翰
Guys, this is my cousin, John.
弟弟
Cousin?
是啊 他今天安了条新腿
Yeah, he finally got a new leg today.
快来看看
Check it out.
还不错吧
Not bad, right?
我再也不用单膝跪地了
No more kneeing on one knee for me anymore.
太棒了
Cool.
很赞吧
Isn't it great?
我告诉她的时候 玛格丽特大喊大叫地
Margaret screamed so loud when I told her.
她一直在说 "好啊好啊"
She was all like "Yes, dude, yes!"
噢天呐 我真的那么说了吗
Aw, geez. Did I really say that?
太棒了 老兄 真是太棒了
That's great, man, that's really great.
你是有什么要说的吗 摩迪凯
Did you have something to say, Mordecai?
啥
What?
你愿意今晚跟我去看"爱之机器人2"吗
Do you want to see "Love Bot 2" with me tonight?
我这儿有两张票
I got a pair of tickets.
就今晚
Tonight?
好呀 当然 我愿意去
Yeah, sure, I'd love too.
好耶 那就说定了
Great. So it's a date then.
嗨 你好吗 CJ
Hey, what's up, CJ?
摩迪凯 这是什么情况
Mordecai, what's going on?
啥
What?
你不是要带我去看电影吗
Aren't you taking me to that movie?
啥
Wha-?
糟了
Shoot.
摩迪凯 她在说什么
Mordecai, what's she talking about?
呃 等等 等一下
Um, wait. Hold on!
大事不妙
Oh, no.
等等 我们可以想法子解决的
Wait, we can work this out.
你说"想法子解决"是什么意思
What do you mean, "work this out"?
等等 摩迪凯 你在跟这个女的交往吗
Wait, Mordecai, are you dating this girl?
啥 没有啊 我们只是朋友 普通朋友
What? No. We're just friends. Just friends.
只是朋友 你怎么可以这么说
Just friends? How can you say that?
啥 可是这是事实啊
Wha-? But it's true.
难以置信 这简直
I can't believe this, this--
太典型了
So typical!
我本以为遇上了好男人 看来我不该这么想
I thought I met a nice guy, but I shouldn't have known.
等等 CJ
Wait, CJ.
你只是在玩弄我的感情吗
Are you just playing some sort of game?
这对你来说只是个游戏吗
Is this a game to you?
啥 不啊
What? No.
你到底还邀请了多少个女孩子去看电影
How many other girls did you invite to this movie?
我只有两张票啊
I only had two tickets!
CJ 冷静
CJ, calm down!
我以为咱们达成了共识
I thought we had an understanding!
达成共识
An understanding?!
老兄 你在搞毛啊
Dude, what are you doing?
你这是火上浇油
You're making it worse.
说点心里话
Say something genuine!
好吧 是我搞砸了
Okay, I messed up!
我忘记了邀请过你去看电影 但是我绝对不是故意的
I forgot I asked you to the same movie, but I didn't mean it like that.
我认识你的时候就告诉过你 我对约会不感兴趣
I told you when we met I wasn't interested in dating.
可我以为你会开始慢慢喜欢我
But I thought you were starting to like me!
我是喜欢你啊
I do like you!
你是个超棒的朋友
You're a really awesome friend!
听着 我知道你喜欢的对你没感觉这件事很伤人
Look, I know it hurts to have feelings for someone who doesn't feel the same,
我也经历过
I've been there!
也许我不能成为那个替你扫除阴霾的人
Maybe I can't be the one to cheer you up,
但无论如何 我很抱歉
but for what it's worth, I'm sorry!
好吧 我懂了
Okay, I get it.
但是你至少该告诉我你心里有人了
But you should've at least told me there was someone else.
没错 我该对你坦诚相待的
You're right. I should've been honest.
咱们还能做朋友吗
Can't we still be friends?
不行
No.
我只是 我不觉得现在还能跟你做朋友
I just...don't think I can be friends with you right now.
再会 摩迪凯
Goodbye, Mordecai.
玛格丽特 你还好吗
Margaret, are you okay?
你现在可是个花心大萝卜了 对吧
So I guess your a big heartbreaker now, huh?
不 这只是 这只是个大误会
No, it's just... It's just a big misunderstanding.
不 这挺好的 你和别人交往挺好的
No, it's good. It's good that your dating.
听着 我们不是真的在交往
Look, we weren't really dating.
等等 你是在吃醋吗
Wait, are you jealous?
什么
What?
你在吃醋 对吧
You are, aren't you?
呃 我 我才没
Um I-- I don't--
你在讲什么鬼 我听不懂
I don't know what you're talking about.
吃点小醋没什么问题哟
It's okay if your a little jealous.
等等 咱们还去看电影吗
But wait, aren't we still gonna the movies?
你想去看电影吗
Do you wanna go to the movie?
不必 我没兴趣了
Nah, I'm over it.
搞毛啊这是
Aw, what?!
那我该跟谁去啊
But who am I gonna go with?
唉 就 湿 这 么 没 逻 机
Love is highy illogical.
唉 窝    唉 窝
Love me. Love me.